<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>All Posts - CUEH ComSec</title><link>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/</link><description>All Posts | CUEH ComSec</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 12:40:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting setup for ComSec</title><link>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/getting-setup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 12:40:28 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/getting-setup/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Most ComSec sessions are practical, so you&rsquo;ll need a system you&rsquo;re happy to hack on. We will run workshops in the labs as much as possible, so those machines will be available. If you&rsquo;re a more experience hacker, you no doubt have your own environment, however, if you&rsquo;re still getting into the area you may want a low-effort environment to start with. ComSec has built some tools to help with this.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Writeup: Hack The Box Cyber Apocalypse 2023 - The Cursed Mission</title><link>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/2023_hackthebox_cyberapoc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 12:40:28 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/2023_hackthebox_cyberapoc/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>The HackTheBox Cyber Apocalypse has become a staple annual event of the ComSec CTF calendar, though this year a couple
of changed were introduced - such as the maximum team size and average difficulty of the challenges. This post
contains some challenges</p>
<div class="toc" id="toc-auto">
    <h2 class="toc-title">Contents</h2>

    <div class="toc-content false" id="toc-content-auto"></div>
</div>

<div class="details toc" id="toc-static"  kept="true">
    <div class="details-summary toc-title">
        <span>Contents</span>
        <span><i class="details-icon fas fa-angle-right"></i></span>
    </div>
    <div class="details-content toc-content" id="toc-content-static"><nav id="TableOfContents">
  <ul>
    <li><a href="#rev-alien-saboteur">rev: Alien Saboteur</a>
      <ul>
        <li><a href="#understanding-the-vm">Understanding the VM</a></li>
        <li><a href="#reversing-the-vm-program">Reversing the VM Program</a></li>
        <li><a href="#getting-the-first-password">Getting the First Password</a></li>
        <li><a href="#unravelling-more-code">Unravelling more Code</a></li>
        <li><a href="#finding-the-flag">Finding the Flag</a></li>
      </ul>
    </li>
    <li><a href="#pwn-control-room">pwn: Control Room</a>
      <ul>
        <li><a href="#static-analysis">Static Analysis</a></li>
      </ul>
    </li>
    <li><a href="#configure-engine">Configure Engine</a></li>
    <li><a href="#exploitation">Exploitation</a></li>
  </ul>
</nav></div>
</div>

<h2 id="rev-alien-saboteur">rev: Alien Saboteur</h2>
<p></p>]]></description></item><item><title>DownUnder CTF 2022</title><link>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/down-under-ctf-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 12:40:28 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/down-under-ctf-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>DownUnder CTF was a 48 hour CTF that began on Friday 23rd September 2022. It was the first CTF of the year that ComSec
played, we had quite a few new members playing this one so it was a great chance for them to practice their skills.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article contains writeups of a range of difficulty and category, so this should be a good place for new members
to see what a jeopardy style CTF looks like.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Log and PATH Poisoning</title><link>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/2022_log_and_path_poisoning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 21:15:26 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/2022_log_and_path_poisoning/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this session we talked about log files, the PATH variable and how an attacker could exploit them. Briefly, the PATH is a system variable unique to UNIX systems which defines the hierarchy that the CPU uses to find executable binaries. If someone were to prepend or append a valid directory to the PATH, then the CPU would consider it as a valid location to find binaries in. Similarly, log files can be used as a vector for code execution if the permissions were to be misconfigured.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SQL Injection</title><link>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/2021_sqli/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 12:40:28 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/2021_sqli/</guid><description><![CDATA[<h1 id="sql-injection">SQL Injection</h1>
<ul>
<li>Further on today, we will be using THM</li>
<li>If you haven&rsquo;t registered go to <a href="https://tryhackme.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">tryhackme.com</a></li>
<li>Ensure you have the <a href="https://tryhackme.com/access" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">VPN file</a> or AttackBox ready</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="sql">SQL</h2>
<p>Structured Query Language (SQL) is used to communicate with databases and has the capability to delete, edit, insert or retrieve data. There are a few variations of SQL which have some slight syntactical differences. A few examples are MySQL, SQL Server and SQLite.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Twelvetide CTF</title><link>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/2021_twelvetide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 12:40:28 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/2021_twelvetide/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Hi everyone,</p>
<p>Hope you&rsquo;re all enjoying yourselves now that coursework deadlines have passed. As Christmas approaches ComSec would like to announce the dates of our Christmas CTF - Twelvetide.</p>
<p>The CTF will last 15 days, with new challenges released every day for the first 12 days. Difficulty will range from entry-level to intermediate, so make sure you sign on and give it a go!</p>
<p>More details will be released on the ComSec discord in coming days. If you are not a member, check our post on Aula, or search for ComSec in your university email contacts.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Walkthrough: Shellcoding Challenges</title><link>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/2021_assembly_and_shellcoding_walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 10:40:28 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/2021_assembly_and_shellcoding_walkthrough/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>As promised by Ben in <a href="https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/2021_assembly_and_shellcoding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Assembly &amp; Shellcoding</a>, this article will cover the solutions for the Shellcode challenges. The challenges can be found on CTFd and is strongly recommended to try to solve the challenges on your own before continue reading this article!</p>
<h2 id="preparation-for-the-challenges">Preparation for the challenges</h2>
<p>Each of the following challenges will require you to send your already assembled code to the target; whose ip address and port is specified in the description of each challenge on CTFd.
The file &lsquo;boilerplate.py&rsquo; was kindly provided and its purpose is to help assemble your code, connect to the host and inject the payload; all you have to do it insert your assembly code where required and type the ip address and port number of the target inside the brackets of the p.remote() method.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Octalkber</title><link>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/octalkber/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 12:40:28 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/octalkber/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Throughout the month of October, for cybersecurity awareness month, each week we will be having a talk by someone in the cybersecurity field. To see our latest line-up and how to gain access to these talks; please refer to the posts in Aula and the ComSec Discord channel.</p>
<p>Thanks,</p>
<p>ComSec</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Scanning and Enumeration</title><link>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/2021_scanning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 22:40:28 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/2021_scanning/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In this session we will begin to look at scanning and enummeration, and start to look at some of the associated tools.</p>
<h2 id="warm-up---getting-help-in-the-terminal">Warm Up - Getting help in the Terminal</h2>
<p>Ever forgotten a command or switch in linux - here&rsquo;s two great ways to find help; all from the comfort of your terminal!</p>
<h3 id="help">&ndash;help</h3>
<p>Virtually all commands in linux have built-in help, all you need to do is append <code>--help</code> to the end of your command. So for help with nmap, you would use</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Week 1: OSINT Chalange Writeup</title><link>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/week1_writeup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 12:40:28 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://cov-comsec.github.io/posts/week1_writeup/</guid><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="intro">Intro</h2>
<p>The first-week challenge covers the basics of OSINT research, opening remote connections and password cracking. I will try to cover most of the methods we can use to get through Jack&rsquo;s cat and Ben&rsquo;s secure passwords. Without further ado, let&rsquo;s begin.</p>
<h2 id="challenge-1-web-username">Challenge 1: Web Username</h2>
<p>The first one was very tricky for me as I am not a cat person and don&rsquo;t enjoy cat pictures&hellip;
Anyway, as we go to the landing page, we can see that there are home(1) and login(2) pages and some information(3) about some employees.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>